**Aditi Dass** 

aditid@bu.edu +1 (857)-272-1725 Github | Linkedin

#### Summary

Recent Masters in Computer Science graduate. 1+ year cumulative experience in full-stack development and applied cryptography. Adept and adaptive learner - previous internship involved different stacks for each new project. Enthusiastic researcher and contributor of digital decentralized systems.

#### **Technical Profile**

Languages Python, JavaScript, C, C#, Java, C++, GoLang Back End Node.js, AJAX, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, PHP

APIs Javax.Crypto, PyCrypto, TensorFlow, Binance, Quantopian

Web Design HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js

### **Experience**

# Software Application and Innovation Lab, Hariri Institute of Computing

Software Developer and Research Intern May 2017 - Aug 2017

- Designed a <u>cryptographic protocol</u> for privacy preserving data aggregation that was adopted by a NIH funded healthcare firm
- Co-managed project to transition backend framework from Java to JavaScript
- Developed AJAX API routes and models for \$1M funded synthetic biological tool
- Implemented algorithm in C# for an untrusted, anonymous digital coin tumbler

#### Software Developer Intern

May 2016 - Jul 2016

- Assessed several open source backend frameworks based on individual project requirements
- Built accessible adaptive survey platform with Node.js frameworks and Ionic

# **Boston University Venture Accelerator, BUZZ Lab**

Boston

**Boston** 

#### Technology Director

Sep 2016 - May 2017

- · Led consultations for startups' website/app development and advised on tech hiring decisions
- Worked with non-technical clients where software had to be illustrated across interdisciplinary fields

Project Manager Sep 2015 - May 2016

 Mentored multiple startups at conception phase in financial modeling and scaling to pitch successfully to investors

#### **Outreach**

## Codebreakers 2016, LERNet

Boston

#### **Undergraduate Coordinator**

Jul 2016 - Aug 2016

- Designed and developed teaching material and agenda for <u>summer program</u>
- Introduced female high schoolers to Python with a focus on cryptography and network security

#### Education

## **Boston University**

**Boston** 

#### BA/MS in Computer Science, Minor in Mechanical Engineering

Sep 2013 - Dec 2017

 Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Distributed Systems, Network Security, Applied Cryptography, Advanced Algorithms, Computer Networks, Software Engineering